<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:news</id>
  <title type="html">Houston.pm: What's New</title>
  <link href="http://houston.pm.org/"/>
  <link href="http://houston.pm.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2019-09-11T12:32:28Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>G. Wade Johnson</name>
  </author>
  <category term="news"/>
  <generator uri="https://metacpan.org/pod/XML::Atom::SimpleFeed" version="0.902">XML::Atom::SimpleFeed</generator>
  <entry>
    <title>Panel Discussion on Object Oriented Programming</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20190911s-1260</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the September Houston.pm meeting, Julian Brown chairs a &lt;em&gt;Panel Discussion on Object Oriented Programming&lt;/em&gt;.
The meeting begins on September 12 at 6pm in the cPanel offices at 2550 North Loop West, Suite 4006.
We gather in the lobby 30 minutes before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This panel discussion covers the basics of Object Oriented Programming. Although OO has been the
dominant paradigm for the last couple of decades, there are still a number of concepts that
people seem to misunderstand. Julian will attempt to wrangle a number of members with many different
levels of experience to discuss OO. The goal is to help all of us come to a mutual understanding
of various aspects of OO.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <updated>2019-09-11T12:32:28Z</updated>
    <published>2019-09-11T12:32:28Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <category term="panel discussion"/>
    <category term="fundamentals"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Basic Unit Testing Concepts in Perl</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20190730s-418</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the August Houston.pm meeting, G. Wade Johnson presents &lt;em&gt;Basic Unit Testing Concepts in Perl&lt;/em&gt;.
The meeting begins on August 8 at 6pm in the Hostgator offices at 5005 Mitchelldale St., Suite 100.
We gather in the lobby 30 minutes before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wade starts with some unit testing basics, introduces some of the Perl unit test frameworks,
and then focuses on concepts and tricks to help you get more from your unit tests. While not
attempting to cover the whole subject of unit testing, there should be something here for most.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <updated>2019-07-30T23:09:21Z</updated>
    <published>2019-07-30T23:09:21Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <category term="unit testing"/>
    <category term="documentation"/>
    <category term="design"/>
    <category term="codecraft"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Test::Spec, test using a declarative testing framework</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20190628s-12863</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the July Houston.pm meeting, Julian Brown presents &lt;em&gt;Test::Spec, test using a declarative testing framework&lt;/em&gt;.
The meeting begins on July 11 at 6pm in the cPanel offices at 2550 North Loop West, Suite 4006.
We gather in the lobby 30 minutes before.&lt;/p&gt;
Julian presents a Perl test module modeled after the Ruby RSpec testing framework.</content>
    <updated>2019-06-28T20:30:53Z</updated>
    <published>2019-06-28T20:30:53Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <category term="testing"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Moving my website toward production</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20190605s-13192</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the June Houston.pm meeting, Julian Brown presents &lt;em&gt;Moving my website toward production&lt;/em&gt;.
The meeting begins on June 13 at 6pm in the HostGator offices at 5005 Mitchelldale St., Suite 100.
We gather in the lobby 30 minutes before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julian will spend a few minutes on the state of his current website project, and where he intends
to take it. He will elicit input from the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julian Brown will spend some time showing and explaining the state of his
current website project, and cover where he intends to take it next&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <updated>2019-06-06T02:04:24Z</updated>
    <published>2019-06-06T02:04:24Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <category term="web development"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Moving my website toward production</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20190605s-10603</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the June Houston.pm meeting, Julian Brown presents &lt;em&gt;Moving my website toward production&lt;/em&gt;.
The meeting begins on June 13 at 6pm in the HostGator offices at 5005 Mitchelldale St., Suite 100.
We gather in the lobby 30 minutes before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julian will spend a few minutes on the state of his current website project, and where he intends
to take it. He will elicit input from the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julian Brown will spend some time showing and explaining the state of his
current website project, and cover where he intends to take it next&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <updated>2019-06-06T02:00:47Z</updated>
    <published>2019-06-06T02:00:47Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <category term="web development"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Getting Started With OpenShift - Using Containers for SysOps and Engineering</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20190428s-26836</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the May Houston.pm meeting, Robert Stone presents &lt;em&gt;Getting Started With OpenShift - Using Containers for SysOps and Engineering&lt;/em&gt;.
The meeting begins on May 9 at 6pm in the cPanel offices at 2550 North Loop West, Suite 4006.
We gather in the lobby 30 minutes before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert will do a demo of OpenShift, showing some of the high points of functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <updated>2019-04-28T23:43:57Z</updated>
    <published>2019-04-28T23:43:57Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <category term="OpenShift"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Notes for 'make-ing a Static Website' posted.</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1903</id>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>G. Wade Johnson has been maintaining the [Houston.pm website](http://houston.pm.org/) for years.
The original hosting for the site was located at pm.org and was maintained by volunteers.
To reduce their work, they required all hosted sites to be static.

Wade had experience a couple of decades back generating static shells for small amounts of
dynamic content.
He applied similar techniques to the Houston.pm website to make it easier to maintain.

## A Little History

   * He took over maintenance in December 2004
   * Originally hosted on the pm.org servers
   * The pm.org servers only supported static content
   * Recently began hosting it on servers he controlled
   * Nov 2002 - mostly empty placeholder
   * Aug 2003 - meeting schedule announced
   * Dec 2005 - the first generated version

The site was maintained manually between December 2004 and December 2005.

## Why a Static Site?

Many people have asked why the site is maintained as static HTML, instead of using a more modern framework or tool.

When he first took over the site maintenace, he did not know how long it would last.
He did not want to start paying for hosting on something that he might not maintain for long.
He figured it would pass to someone else after a few years.
Additionally, the site itself had no compelling need for dynamic features.
He also was only willing to spend a limited amount of time maintaining it.

At different times in the past, people have recommended converting to a <abbr title="Content Management System">CMS</abbr>
or Wiki to maintain the site. Both of these approaches would require work to convert the content that
currently exists and on-going maintenance and security monitoring to keep them functional.
Wade is not really interested in generating extra work for himself for dubious benefits.

## Why Generate a Static Site

The first major rewrite of the site (2005) moved to the first version of the generating code.

The main reasons for generating the site are:

   * Consistent look/style (such as it is)
   * Code for creating new pages
   * Site is under [version control](http://github.com/gwadej/houstonpm/)
   * Based loosely on the results of his Masters Thesis

Since all of the generating code is in relatively straight-forward Perl 5 code, it should be easy for another maintainer to pick up.
If anyone wants to make changes, they are free to send a pull request on github.
If a change does not make his life harder, Wade says he will probably accept it.

## The Code

At this point, Wade went to the source on GitHub and began walking through some of the core features.

There are a number generic templates in the [templates/](https://github.com/gwadej/houstonpm/tree/master/templates) directory.
Some of these are fragments used by other templates.
Others are more or less standalone templates.
A number of templates are wrappers defining the general structure of certain pages:

templates/index_wrap.tt2
:  the main index page of the site
templates/main_wrap.tt2
:  any main page besides the index
templates/talks_wrap.tt2
:  the recent talks and year talks pages
templates/writeup_wrap.tt2
:  the talk write-up pages

Other core templates include:

templates/copyright.tt2
:  specifies the copyright notice on each page, handling appropriate year information and licensing
templates/main_menu.tt2
:  specifies the left-hand menu for the site
templates/recenttalks.tt2
:  page listing the most recent talks
templates/yeartalks.tt2
:  page listing all of the talks for a given year

The whole system is driven by a [Makefile](https://github.com/gwadej/houstonpm/blob/master/Makefile).
The Makefile contains quite a bit of redundant information.
This turns out not to be a big maintenance problem, because the Makefile is generated from a template ([templates/Makefile.tt2](https://github.com/gwadej/houstonpm/blob/master/templates/Makefile.tt2)).

## Scripts

In the [bin/](https://github.com/gwadej/houstonpm/blob/master/bin/) directory are a set of scripts that Wade uses to build the site.
The `bin/talks.pl` script is used to convert the information from the `talks.xml` document into all of the yearly and recent pages.
The `bin/announce.pl` script updates the `atom.xml` file which supports feed readers (if anyone still uses them).
It also provides the message used to update the mailing list and such when announcing a new meeting.
The `bin/writeup.pl` script helps in the construction of the write-ups for each meeting.
Among other things, it

   * asks the maintainer for information about the talk
   * creates the appropriate directory structure
   * leads through writing up the talk
   * builds a <abbr title="Template Toolkit">TT</abbr> file for the write-up

## Legacies

Wade explained that there are some legacy bits due to the length of time this project has run.
The `talks.xml` document is basically a database of the talks through time.
Since the information is basically a series of short documents, it hasn't been worth any effort to turn it into a more traditional database.
Some of the transformation work done to extract data from the talks file is performed through <abbr title="eXtensible Stylesheet Language">XSL</abbr> files.
This approach has mostly been abandoned, but was a viable system at the turn of the century.

## Conclusion

The audience had a number of questions about particular design decisions.
Some of the comments made valid suggestions of other design trade-offs.
In the end, many of the decisions made on this system were simply what was easiest at the time.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <updated>2019-03-19T19:26:19Z</updated>
    <published>2019-03-19T19:26:19Z</published>
    <link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2019talks/1903Talk/index.html"/>
    <category term="presentation"/>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Subtle Magic: Moving to Dancer2/DBIx::Class/TT</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20190316-6823</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The April meeting will be held at HostGator, at 
5005 Mitchelldale, Suite #100, Houston, Texas, on April 11. We will
meet in the lobby between 5:30pm and 6. Once everyone arrives, we head inside
for the meeting at 6pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, Ruth Holloway will present &lt;em&gt;Subtle Magic: Moving to Dancer2/DBIx::Class/TT&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Read the documentation", we're told, but there's always more to learn. When
I started working with Dancer2, DBIx::Class, and Template Toolkit last fall,
I'd seen the basics, but I found out &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; quickly that there's much more to
learn. The capabilities of this stack can influence application design from the
ground up database tables, all the way to the final frameworks you might choose
to use on the frontend, and not all of those repercussions are immediately
clear from merely reading the documentation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we'll learn about some of the strengths of these modules and
demonstrate how their capabilities can be leveraged to help you work faster and
write great web-based applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <updated>2019-03-17T04:03:47Z</updated>
    <published>2019-03-17T04:03:47Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>make-ing a Static Website</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20190313-12399</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember static websites? Back when the web was new?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month, G. Wade Johnson will present how he generates the static website houston.pm.org and why.
There will be Perl. There will be Template Toolkit. There will be markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, we will meet in the lobby at cPanel, Inc. starting at 5:30pm on Thursday, March 14.
At 6pm, we will go up to the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <updated>2019-03-13T23:26:32Z</updated>
    <published>2019-03-13T23:26:32Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Notes for 'Automating multi-server workflows with Ansible' posted.</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1902</id>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>J. D. Lightsey describes how he has used Ansible as a workflow system to automate processes for some personal servers.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <updated>2019-03-11T00:36:30Z</updated>
    <published>2019-03-11T00:36:30Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2019talks/1902Talk/index.html"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Notes for 'Looking back to 2018, what I learnt from XS and Dist::Zilla' posted.</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1901</id>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Nicolas Rochelemagne gave a little retrospective of 2018.
He included a best of section and some lessons he learned concerning DistZilla and XS.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <updated>2019-03-10T20:22:02Z</updated>
    <published>2019-03-10T20:22:02Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2019talks/1901Talk/index.html"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Notes for 'Testing the untestable with Test::MockFile' posted.</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1811</id>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Todd Rinaldo described the difficulty with testing file-level checks on a system administration tool.
He describes the testing and a new module to solve this problem.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <updated>2019-03-10T18:30:25Z</updated>
    <published>2019-03-10T18:30:25Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2018talks/1811Talk/index.html"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Notes for 'Monolithic vs Microservice: Can Davids Really Take Down Goliath?' posted.</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1810</id>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Robert Stone presented a comparison between the monolithic style of architecture and a microservices style.
He highlighted the benefits of the microservices style to show the advantages of a change.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <updated>2019-03-10T16:57:25Z</updated>
    <published>2019-03-10T16:57:25Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2018talks/1810Talk/index.html"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Notes for 'Performance of Parsing Short Strings' posted.</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1809</id>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>G. Wade Johnson presents the results of some benchmarking of different approaches to parsing
short text strings.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <updated>2019-01-30T04:38:24Z</updated>
    <published>2019-01-30T04:38:24Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2018talks/1809Talk/index.html"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Notes for 'Julian in the land of NoSQL' posted.</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1808</id>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Julian Brown explores the usage of the Arangodb NoSQL database as used a website he's working on.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <updated>2019-01-29T03:38:41Z</updated>
    <published>2019-01-29T03:38:41Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2018talks/1808Talk/index.html"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Notes for 'Using Perl to Learn a Foreign Language' posted.</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1807</id>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Mark Allen decided to cut back on his Twitter use. Since he now needed a new smartphone activity,
he turned to DuoLingo and began studying Russian. This lead to the construction of a Perl
module to handle declining Russian pronouns, adjectives, and nouns.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <updated>2019-01-28T03:40:02Z</updated>
    <published>2019-01-28T03:40:02Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2018talks/1807Talk/index.html"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Notes for 'Floccus, an adventure in Ecmascript 8' posted.</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1806</id>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Julian Brown described attempting to add a feature to a tool for synchronizing bookmarks.
In the process, he learned about ECMAScript 8. This presentation explores what he learned.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <updated>2019-01-28T01:30:53Z</updated>
    <published>2019-01-28T01:30:53Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2018talks/1806Talk/index.html"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Notes for 'Threat Modeling' posted.</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1805</id>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>J. D. Lightsey gave a quick overview of the concept of Threat Modeling and demonstrated approaches for doing threat modeling.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <updated>2019-01-27T22:45:57Z</updated>
    <published>2019-01-27T22:45:57Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2018talks/1805Talk/index.html"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Notes for 'Comparison of Rails and Dancer2' posted.</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1804</id>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>G. Wade Johnson demonstrates a simple web application built in both Ruby on Rails and Dancer2 on Perl.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <updated>2019-01-27T20:12:35Z</updated>
    <published>2019-01-27T20:12:35Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2018talks/1804Talk/index.html"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Notes for 'AWStats Flaws and Making a Cute Robot with Perl' posted.</title>
    <id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1803</id>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>This month was a pair of presentations. Mark Gardner described building a robot
project for a GEMS conference. JD Lightsey followed up with a dive into security
flaws in the AWStats program.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <updated>2019-01-27T17:27:36Z</updated>
    <published>2019-01-27T17:27:36Z</published>
    <category term="technical meeting"/>
    <link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2018talks/1803Talk/index.html"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
