<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:news</id><title type="html">Houston.pm: What&#39;s New</title><link href="http://houston.pm.org/"/><link href="http://houston.pm.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/><updated>2017-11-06T02:23:50Z</updated><author><name>G. Wade Johnson</name></author><category term="news"/><generator uri="https://metacpan.org/pod/XML::Atom::SimpleFeed" version="0.861">XML::Atom::SimpleFeed</generator><entry><updated>2017-11-06T02:14:07Z</updated><published>2017-11-06T02:14:07Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20171105-32084</id><title>Hacking Perl Source</title><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following on last month&#39;s design hack, we&#39;re going to attempt to
actually troubleshoot and hack the Perl source for this month&#39;s meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll find a ticket in RT or a new bug in Perl and as a group, we&#39;ll provide
a fix to upstream. This gives us an opportunity to help the Perl community and
learn about the inner workings of Perl at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Design Hack</title><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This month we&#39;re going to try to do a group design hack. We will start
with a problem the group has agreed on and work through the process of coming
up with an initial design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial proposal is a PSGI Web server package that only requires a single
configuration file to have a web server up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not expect to finish coding this at the meeting, but we would like to
have an initial design before the end of the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><published>2017-10-09T02:16:21Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20171008-21100</id><updated>2017-10-09T02:16:21Z</updated></entry><entry><published>2017-08-18T03:50:20Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1708</id><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Gray-ish Hat Adventures In Automating Mobile Game Play: Why Tap When You Could Automate?&#39; posted.</title><category term="technical meeting"/><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Robert Stone describes the troubleshooting techniques he used to reverse
engineer a game to see if he could automate some of the boring parts of the
game.</p></div></content><updated>2017-08-18T03:50:20Z</updated><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1708Talk/index.html"/></entry><entry><updated>2017-08-08T23:14:09Z</updated><title>Gray-ish Hat Adventures In Automating Mobile Game Play: Why Tap When You Could Automate?</title><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most mobile games are highly repetitive and require hours of &#34;Grinding&#34;
which is the boring part of the game you have to do (or pay to bypass) in
order to get stronger.  In fact, this is the entire freemium business model
and I&#39;m willing to bet you have more then a few of these games installed on
your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn&#39;t it be great if you could figure out what the game was doing with
each of these taps and automate it?  Why stop there, you could create your
own army and dominate the virtual landscape finally putting that college
education to use!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us as we walk through just this process for a very popular mobile game
that shall remain nameless (because I like the game and don&#39;t want to get
banned!) but all shall be revealed at our next meeting.  There will be a
real-time walk through of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Demo of the Game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decompiling the app using JADX and JetBrains.dotPeek&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reverse engineering the API the game uses by way of BlueStacks, Charles,
and ProxyCap.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating a WebSocket client ( using Moo as a change of pace from Moose )
to simulate what the app does, automating the boring grind-y parts of the
game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If time permits a discussion on Moo versus Moose thoughts will be
provided.  Bring your mobile phones and your perlbrew, for we shall tear
those meddling do-gooders asunder.  Mwwwwwwhahahahaa!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><published>2017-08-08T23:14:09Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20170808-19574</id></entry><entry><published>2017-07-30T05:00:17Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1707</id><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Getting gutsy with perl5&#39; posted.</title><category term="technical meeting"/><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Todd Rinaldo has been working on the guts of Perl recently as part of the Perl
compiler project at cPanel. He began with some of the pre-requisites needed to
understand the presentation, including a basic understanding of C:

<ul>
    <li>structures</li>
    <li>unions</li>
    <li>arrays</li>
    <li>typedefs</li>
    <li>#define</li>
</ul>

He showed Nicolas Rochelemagne's talk <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zNsew4U-quM"
target="blank">Introduction to Perl Internals</a> to give some background. Nicolas
covered some of the basics of Perl internal data structures and some information
about how perl handles memory.

After the video, Todd explained the <code>B::C</code> module and some of its
siblings.  He explained the difference between a stash and a pad, and talked
about how new pads are added each time you add a scope. Todd spent a little
more time discussing the internal data structures, mostly focusing on how they
relate to stashes and pads.

Next, he discussed how the parser doesn't actually generate an op-tree, as you might
guess from an study of compilers. Instead, it generates several op-trees, that are
linked together by entries in the stashes. He recommended spending time studying
Reini Urban's <a href="https://github.com/rurban/illguts" target="_blank">Ill Guts</a>
if you are going to spend any time understanding this stuff.

He spent some time discussing some of what cPanel is using the compiler for and what
they hoped to accomplish. He discussed some ideas about optimizing op-trees.

The talk generated several interesting discussions, that branched off the main topic
at times.</p></div></content><updated>2017-07-30T05:00:17Z</updated><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1707Talk/index.html"/></entry><entry><updated>2017-07-06T21:24:26Z</updated><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20170706-23755</id><published>2017-07-06T21:24:26Z</published><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Todd Rinaldo wikk dive into the basics of how Perl data structures work under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><title>Getting gutsy with perl5</title></entry><entry><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1706Talk/index.html"/><updated>2017-07-06T04:34:04Z</updated><category term="technical meeting"/><title type="html">Notes for &#39;OC.pm Coding challenge&#39; posted.</title><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>JD Lightsey suggested that the group make an attempt at the Perl Programming
challenge that OC.pm proposed for their May 2017 meeting. Eveyone was suggested
to make an attempt.</p></div></content><published>2017-07-06T04:34:04Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1706</id></entry><entry><updated>2017-07-06T03:21:24Z</updated><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1705Talk/index.html"/><published>2017-07-06T03:21:24Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1705</id><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Live Code Reviews&#39; posted.</title><category term="technical meeting"/><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The goal this meeting was to do some code reviews as a group. The idea was that
we would learn from each other's techniques and knowledge.</p></div></content></entry><entry><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1704</id><published>2017-07-05T03:45:34Z</published><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Todd Rinaldo discussed the p5hack hack-a-thon this year in Amsterdam. He
described the purpose of the meeting and some of the decisions that came
out of the meeting.</p></div></content><title type="html">Notes for &#39;p5hack&#39; posted.</title><category term="technical meeting"/><updated>2017-07-05T03:45:34Z</updated><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1704Talk/index.html"/></entry><entry><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1703Talk/index.html"/><updated>2017-07-05T03:14:09Z</updated><category term="technical meeting"/><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Maintaining Developer Mental and Physical Health&#39; posted.</title><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Jim Bacon, Robert Stone, and Jocelyn Kirby gave short presentations on health
topics that can apply to developers.</p></div></content><published>2017-07-05T03:14:09Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1703</id></entry><entry><published>2017-06-05T12:30:59Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20170605-11184</id><title>June Houston.pm meeting: Coding Challenge</title><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our June meeting is this Thursday (June 8), at the Hostgator offices
(5005 Mitchelldale St, Ste. 100), starting at 7pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be trying something different again this month. Several members of
the group have agreed to attempt the &lt;a href=&#34;http://oc.pm.org/may_challenge.html&#34;&gt;Orange
County PM coding challenge&lt;/a&gt; this month. The idea is that we should all make
an attempt to solve the challenge and anyone who wishes can demonstrate their
attempt at this Thursday&#39;s meeting. At a minimum, we should get to see how other
people approached an interesting coding challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><updated>2017-06-05T12:30:59Z</updated></entry><entry><updated>2017-05-09T01:00:34Z</updated><published>2017-05-09T01:00:34Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20170508-19563</id><title>Live code reviews</title><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The group will be performing live code reviews of a small number of modules.
Some of the members will drive reviews with different focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry><entry><published>2017-04-09T22:56:02Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20170409-26268</id><title>April Houston.pm meeting: A Discussion About p5hack</title><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;At the April meeting, Todd Rinaldo will tell about a recent visit to p5hack and lead a
discussion on what is coming to Perl. The meeting will be held at Hostgator, on Thursday,
April 13, starting at 7pm.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><updated>2017-04-09T22:56:02Z</updated></entry><entry><updated>2017-03-06T05:02:57Z</updated><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20170305-17867</id><published>2017-03-06T05:02:57Z</published><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our next meeting is this Thursday, March 9 at cPanel. As usual, we
will meet in the lobby and head up to the meeting at 7pm. This month
will be a bit difference, with a combination of presentations and
discussion about keeping ourselves healthy and functional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Robert Stone will lead a discussion on physical health&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jocelyn Kirby will present on friends and levels of communication&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;G. Wade Johnson will lead a discussion on burnout&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other topics as the group decides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><title>Maintaining Developer Mental and Physical Health</title></entry><entry><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1702Talk/index.html"/><updated>2017-02-20T02:46:43Z</updated><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Homophonic Substitution Cipher: Cracking the Code of a Killer&#39; posted.</title><category term="technical meeting"/><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Robert Stone delves into the cipher used by the Zodiac Killer in his
newspaper announcements. He describes substitution ciphers and then
shows how a homophonic substitution cipher fixes many of its problems.
He ends by describing how the Zodiac Killer's cipher was solved.</p></div></content><published>2017-02-20T02:46:43Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1702</id></entry><entry><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;q&gt;I&#39;ve been doing some work with the Zodiac Killer&#39;s Z408 Cipher (I&#39;m tons of fun at cocktail parties!) which is a Homophonic Substitution Cipher. Namely, creating a new Crypt::Z408 module and experimenting with a way to brute force generic Homophonic Substitution Ciphers which may or may not bear fruit.&lt;/q&gt; -- Robert Stone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><title>Homophonic Substitution Ciphers - Cracking The Code of a Killer</title><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20170205-20464</id><published>2017-02-05T18:45:45Z</published><updated>2017-02-05T18:45:45Z</updated></entry><entry><updated>2017-02-05T02:05:01Z</updated><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/170126Talk/index.html"/><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:170126</id><published>2017-02-05T02:05:01Z</published><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Reini Urban gave a presentation highlighting several of the features of the
cperl fork of the perl programming language.</p></div></content><category term="technical meeting"/><title type="html">Notes for &#39;cperl&#39; posted.</title></entry><entry><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Tonight's meeting featured a set of short talks on various topics.
Robert Stone did a talk on TDD. Julian Brown presented a kind of
radix sort that the inventer claims is faster than the standard Perl
sort. Jocelyn Kirby presented about Sessions in web applications.
G. Wade Johnson presented some vim tips. And, Michael R. Davis
finished the presentations with an introduction to some of his
CPAN modules.</p></div></content><category term="technical meeting"/><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Lightning Talks&#39; posted.</title><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1701</id><published>2017-02-03T04:26:29Z</published><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1701Talk/index.html"/><updated>2017-02-03T04:26:29Z</updated></entry><entry><updated>2017-01-24T23:16:58Z</updated><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reini Urban will talk about the cperl fork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><title>Houston.pm Special meeting: Reini Urban on cperl</title><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20170124-29870</id><published>2017-01-24T23:16:58Z</published></entry><entry><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This month various members are going to give short talks on various topics of
interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><title>Lightning/short talks</title><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20170109-29534</id><published>2017-01-10T02:00:56Z</published><updated>2017-01-10T02:00:56Z</updated></entry><entry><updated>2016-11-18T04:32:49Z</updated><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2016talks/1611Talk/index.html"/><published>2016-11-18T04:32:49Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1611</id><category term="technical meeting"/><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Pragmatic Functional Programming in Perl&#39; posted.</title><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Last month's talk covered a bit of functional programming theory and why it
teaches you more about programming. This month Wade focuses on the aspects of
functional programming you can apply today in your own Perl code.</p></div></content></entry><entry><published>2016-11-03T03:06:25Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20161102-28114</id><title>Pragmatic Functional Programming in Perl</title><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ve heard the arguments on why functional programming is the wave of the
future. You&#39;ve seen the techniques used in other functional languages. And now,
you&#39;re wondering &#34;How does this apply to my day-to-day code?&#34;. G. Wade Johnson
covers how some of these techniques can apply in your day-to-day programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><updated>2016-11-03T03:06:25Z</updated></entry></feed>