<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:news</id><title type="html">Houston.pm: What&#39;s New</title><link href="http://houston.pm.org/"/><link href="http://houston.pm.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/><updated>2018-04-27T04:23:07Z</updated><author><name>G. Wade Johnson</name></author><category term="news"/><generator uri="https://metacpan.org/pod/XML::Atom::SimpleFeed" version="0.861">XML::Atom::SimpleFeed</generator><entry><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20180426-5758</id><title>Threat Modeling</title><published>2018-04-27T04:21:05Z</published><updated>2018-04-27T04:21:05Z</updated><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;At the May 10 Houston.pm meeting, JD Lightsey will do a presentation
explaining threat modeling. He will continue with a game that helps the
audience exercise their new threat modeling knowledge. We will meet at
cPanel at 7pm.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry><entry><published>2018-04-19T11:28:03Z</published><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Ruby for Perl Programmers&#39; posted.</title><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1802</id><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2018talks/1802Talk/index.html"/><updated>2018-04-19T11:28:03Z</updated><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>G. Wade Johnson presented his impressions about being a professional
Ruby programmer for the last 2.5 years, contrasted with his experience
as a Perl programmer.</p></div></content><category term="technical meeting"/></entry><entry><updated>2018-04-18T11:44:34Z</updated><category term="technical meeting"/><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Julian Brown presented the results of his look into the Bedrock project. This project builds a distributed
database on top of SQLite.</p></div></content><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1801</id><title type="html">Notes for &#39;A Look at Bedrock, a Distributed SQLite DB&#39; posted.</title><published>2018-04-18T11:44:34Z</published><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2018talks/1801Talk/index.html"/></entry><entry><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Todd leads a session to hack on Perl code from the RT queue. The idea is
to find and fix at least one bug as a team.</p></div></content><updated>2018-04-17T11:37:58Z</updated><category term="technical meeting"/><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1711</id><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Perl Source Hack&#39; posted.</title><published>2018-04-17T11:37:58Z</published><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1711Talk/index.html"/></entry><entry><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20180405-12369</id><published>2018-04-05T12:16:08Z</published><title>Comparison of Rails and Dancer2</title><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In this month&#39;s presentation, G. Wade Johnson will cover his experiment creating
the same basic web application in Ruby on Rails and Dancer2 on Perl. Since he has not
created many applications on either platform, this is close to a first timer experience
for each.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><updated>2018-04-05T12:16:08Z</updated></entry><entry><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This month, we have two shorter topics that we will cover. JD Lightsey
will cover another security topic with &lt;em&gt;AWStats Flaws&lt;/em&gt;. Mark Gardner
will delve into robotics using Perl and a Raspberry Pi.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><updated>2018-03-04T05:01:38Z</updated><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20180303-22217</id><published>2018-03-04T05:01:38Z</published><title>AWStats Flaws and Making a Cure Robot with Perl and Raspberry Pi</title></entry><entry><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20180205-28222</id><title type="html">Ruby Programming from a Perl Programmer&#39;s Point of View</title><published>2018-02-05T13:15:50Z</published><updated>2018-02-05T13:15:50Z</updated><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;G. Wade Johnson presents some comparisons between Ruby and Perl from the
point of view of a long-time Perl programmer working on a Ruby on Rails shop
for the last couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry><entry><updated>2018-01-04T13:09:57Z</updated><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Julian Brown has been looking at the Bedrock distributed database front end
for SQLite. He has a short presentation to present what he has found.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;If time permits, G. Wade Johnson will give a report on Ruby on Rails as
seen by a long-time Perl programmer.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20180104-12293</id><published>2018-01-04T13:09:57Z</published><title>A look at Bedrock, a distributed SQLite DB</title></entry><entry><category term="technical meeting"/><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Julian Brown ran a session where the attendees worked on the initial design
brainstorming for a project. We started with an idea proposed by Michael Davis
for a PSGI package that would set up a web service with minimal configuration.</p></div></content><updated>2017-11-23T16:16:37Z</updated><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1710Talk/index.html"/><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1710</id><published>2017-11-23T16:16:37Z</published><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Design Hack&#39; posted.</title></entry><entry><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1709Talk/index.html"/><published>2017-11-07T04:47:57Z</published><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Web Framework Comparisons&#39; posted.</title><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1709</id><category term="technical meeting"/><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Three different people demonstrated different approaches to developing a web application.
One showed a Dancer-based note taking app. Another showed how mod_perl has different
trade-offs than a framework. The last showed a simple single page CGI script. Then, we
saw info about an attack on suid. The final presentation talked about Perl's minimum
perfect hashes.</p></div></content><updated>2017-11-07T04:47:57Z</updated></entry><entry><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following on last month&#39;s design hack, we&#39;re going to attempt to
actually troubleshoot and hack the Perl source for this month&#39;s meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll find a ticket in RT or a new bug in Perl and as a group, we&#39;ll provide
a fix to upstream. This gives us an opportunity to help the Perl community and
learn about the inner workings of Perl at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><updated>2017-11-06T02:14:07Z</updated><published>2017-11-06T02:14:07Z</published><title>Hacking Perl Source</title><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20171105-32084</id></entry><entry><updated>2017-10-09T02:16:21Z</updated><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This month we&#39;re going to try to do a group design hack. We will start
with a problem the group has agreed on and work through the process of coming
up with an initial design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial proposal is a PSGI Web server package that only requires a single
configuration file to have a web server up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not expect to finish coding this at the meeting, but we would like to
have an initial design before the end of the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><title>Design Hack</title><published>2017-10-09T02:16:21Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20171008-21100</id></entry><entry><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Robert Stone describes the troubleshooting techniques he used to reverse
engineer a game to see if he could automate some of the boring parts of the
game.</p></div></content><category term="technical meeting"/><updated>2017-08-18T03:50:20Z</updated><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1708Talk/index.html"/><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1708</id><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Gray-ish Hat Adventures In Automating Mobile Game Play: Why Tap When You Could Automate?&#39; posted.</title><published>2017-08-18T03:50:20Z</published></entry><entry><title>Gray-ish Hat Adventures In Automating Mobile Game Play: Why Tap When You Could Automate?</title><published>2017-08-08T23:14:09Z</published><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20170808-19574</id><updated>2017-08-08T23:14:09Z</updated><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most mobile games are highly repetitive and require hours of &#34;Grinding&#34;
which is the boring part of the game you have to do (or pay to bypass) in
order to get stronger.  In fact, this is the entire freemium business model
and I&#39;m willing to bet you have more then a few of these games installed on
your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn&#39;t it be great if you could figure out what the game was doing with
each of these taps and automate it?  Why stop there, you could create your
own army and dominate the virtual landscape finally putting that college
education to use!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us as we walk through just this process for a very popular mobile game
that shall remain nameless (because I like the game and don&#39;t want to get
banned!) but all shall be revealed at our next meeting.  There will be a
real-time walk through of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Demo of the Game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decompiling the app using JADX and JetBrains.dotPeek&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reverse engineering the API the game uses by way of BlueStacks, Charles,
and ProxyCap.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating a WebSocket client ( using Moo as a change of pace from Moose )
to simulate what the app does, automating the boring grind-y parts of the
game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If time permits a discussion on Moo versus Moose thoughts will be
provided.  Bring your mobile phones and your perlbrew, for we shall tear
those meddling do-gooders asunder.  Mwwwwwwhahahahaa!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry><entry><category term="technical meeting"/><updated>2017-07-30T05:00:17Z</updated><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Todd Rinaldo has been working on the guts of Perl recently as part of the Perl
compiler project at cPanel. He began with some of the pre-requisites needed to
understand the presentation, including a basic understanding of C:

<ul>
    <li>structures</li>
    <li>unions</li>
    <li>arrays</li>
    <li>typedefs</li>
    <li>#define</li>
</ul>

He showed Nicolas Rochelemagne's talk <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zNsew4U-quM"
target="blank">Introduction to Perl Internals</a> to give some background. Nicolas
covered some of the basics of Perl internal data structures and some information
about how perl handles memory.

After the video, Todd explained the <code>B::C</code> module and some of its
siblings.  He explained the difference between a stash and a pad, and talked
about how new pads are added each time you add a scope. Todd spent a little
more time discussing the internal data structures, mostly focusing on how they
relate to stashes and pads.

Next, he discussed how the parser doesn't actually generate an op-tree, as you might
guess from an study of compilers. Instead, it generates several op-trees, that are
linked together by entries in the stashes. He recommended spending time studying
Reini Urban's <a href="https://github.com/rurban/illguts" target="_blank">Ill Guts</a>
if you are going to spend any time understanding this stuff.

He spent some time discussing some of what cPanel is using the compiler for and what
they hoped to accomplish. He discussed some ideas about optimizing op-trees.

The talk generated several interesting discussions, that branched off the main topic
at times.</p></div></content><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1707</id><published>2017-07-30T05:00:17Z</published><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Getting gutsy with perl5&#39; posted.</title><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1707Talk/index.html"/></entry><entry><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Todd Rinaldo wikk dive into the basics of how Perl data structures work under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><updated>2017-07-06T21:24:26Z</updated><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20170706-23755</id><published>2017-07-06T21:24:26Z</published><title>Getting gutsy with perl5</title></entry><entry><updated>2017-07-06T04:34:04Z</updated><category term="technical meeting"/><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>JD Lightsey suggested that the group make an attempt at the Perl Programming
challenge that OC.pm proposed for their May 2017 meeting. Eveyone was suggested
to make an attempt.</p></div></content><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1706</id><published>2017-07-06T04:34:04Z</published><title type="html">Notes for &#39;OC.pm Coding challenge&#39; posted.</title><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1706Talk/index.html"/></entry><entry><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1705</id><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Live Code Reviews&#39; posted.</title><published>2017-07-06T03:21:24Z</published><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1705Talk/index.html"/><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The goal this meeting was to do some code reviews as a group. The idea was that
we would learn from each other's techniques and knowledge.</p></div></content><category term="technical meeting"/><updated>2017-07-06T03:21:24Z</updated></entry><entry><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1704Talk/index.html"/><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1704</id><published>2017-07-05T03:45:34Z</published><title type="html">Notes for &#39;p5hack&#39; posted.</title><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Todd Rinaldo discussed the p5hack hack-a-thon this year in Amsterdam. He
described the purpose of the meeting and some of the decisions that came
out of the meeting.</p></div></content><updated>2017-07-05T03:45:34Z</updated><category term="technical meeting"/></entry><entry><link href="http://houston.pm.org/talks/2017talks/1703Talk/index.html"/><published>2017-07-05T03:14:09Z</published><title type="html">Notes for &#39;Maintaining Developer Mental and Physical Health&#39; posted.</title><id>tag:houston.pm.org,2011-03:presentation:1703</id><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Jim Bacon, Robert Stone, and Jocelyn Kirby gave short presentations on health
topics that can apply to developers.</p></div></content><category term="technical meeting"/><updated>2017-07-05T03:14:09Z</updated></entry><entry><published>2017-06-05T12:30:59Z</published><title>June Houston.pm meeting: Coding Challenge</title><id>tag:houston.pm.org.2011-03:announce-20170605-11184</id><updated>2017-06-05T12:30:59Z</updated><content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our June meeting is this Thursday (June 8), at the Hostgator offices
(5005 Mitchelldale St, Ste. 100), starting at 7pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be trying something different again this month. Several members of
the group have agreed to attempt the &lt;a href=&#34;http://oc.pm.org/may_challenge.html&#34;&gt;Orange
County PM coding challenge&lt;/a&gt; this month. The idea is that we should all make
an attempt to solve the challenge and anyone who wishes can demonstrate their
attempt at this Thursday&#39;s meeting. At a minimum, we should get to see how other
people approached an interesting coding challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry></feed>